Emerson Sylas L. Lati

Pasig City, Philippines +(63) 995-004-9623 lati.emersonsylas@gmail.com

Profile

Experienced web developer with almost 3 years of experience in developing and designing responsive web pages, creating frontend boilerplates, integrating APIs, and maintaining and updating existing web pages. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP. Strong problem-solving abilities and a passion for staying updated with the latest trends and technologies in web development.

Experience

JULY 2023 - JANUARY 2024

Collabera Digital, Makati City - Web Developer

- Designed and developed responsive web pages for a company website using Vue.js, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, and Figma.
- Developed frontend boilerplates using Vue.js.
- Collaborated with backend developers for API integration and deployments.
- Improved and maintained existing web applications according to clients' requests and requirements.

MARCH 2021 - JUNE 2023

City Government of San Juan, San Juan City - Web Developer

- Designed and developed a web application for creating, viewing, modifying, and scheduling draft and approved resolutions and ordinances using Laravel, Bootstrap, and MySQL.
- Collaborated with senior developers for the deployment of the website and web application.
- Developed a user friendly website for public viewing of city ordinances and resolutions using Laravel.
- Performed minor IT troubleshooting.

JUNE 2019 - NOVEMBER 2020

Tsukiden Global Solution Inc., Makati City - Software Quality Assurance Engineer

- Developed tests using Microsoft Excel for unit testing.
- Collaborated with senior design engineers to ensure the accuracy of the test results.
- Checked and reviewed C language source code for bugs.

Education

APRII 2019

Jose Rizal University, Mandaluyong City - Bachelor's of Science in Computer Engineering

Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP

Frameworks: Laravel, Vue.js, Node.js, Express, Bootstrap

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL

Other tools: jQuery, Git, Github, Bitbucket, Tailwind CSS, Figma, Postman